体中の細胞に火を起こすように
めいっぱいに空気を吸い込んだ
血と汗を煮えに
憧れを精化に
フルーボリュームで叫べよ
光あれ
Oh, yeah.
光あれ、大地へ避ける理由はたったひとつ
光あれ、もっと眩く俺は僕
光あれ、君の今日の輝きが
迷える友の明日を照らすよ
光あれ、君の日を照らすよ
Listen up children. Reblocking works. It takes persistence, training, and endurance.
And when you master it, you'll always get the last laugh.
One chance!
Get that chance ball!
That leaves us with no choice but to attack.
A minus tempo.
Back attack!
Do it!
Get it Taichi!
Shirabu!
What?
It's a strike!
And now!
Hinaja!
Follow up Kageyama!
Hey!
You okay dude?
Yeah!
It's in!
Got it!
Damn!
They returned it to a bad spot!
Well, no time to hesitate!
Pushylock out!
It's off!
Damn!
I wish that set was for me!
But...
I guess I do want to see his spikes!
It's just that...
Sometimes that's frustrating too!
Here it comes!
This is the first time today that they're using a three-man block to stop a straight!
So when it's the final push, we will use a three-man block to close out a straight, not a cross-court shot.
We'll use a few plays to prepare the bait for this trap.
With the repetition of our three-man blocks, we'll make it look like we have a flaw, that we just use them to cover cross-court shots.
As long as our timing is spot-on, there won't be any opportunity for the ball to go anywhere else.
We'll let Ishiwaka get comfortable in knowing we have a hole in our defense.
He'll think he can send us straight right through.
Even though he was breaking his form, he was still able to nail a cross-court shot!
Damn it!
Damn it all!
It's just too damn good!
Damn it!
Asai!
Save it!
Chance ball!
Damn it!
Ten's coming!
He's not flying up front yet.
He's slowing down his tempo from Minus down to first.
Then, he's joining the group.
Shit, no way!
Yeah, right there.
Ah!
Volleyball is a sport where height advantage can take you far.
Naturally, the taller the player, the stronger they are.
However, it is also a strength to perfect your individual skill.
New defenses, attacks, and setups are born in the fray,
which makes this great sport ever-revolving.
Strength can come in many forms.
As the great coach Ari Selinger once said,
there is no reason to not believe that advancement and revolution will come in the future.
And it has never been more true.
Oh, my...
What?
What? This can't be for real?
Hey, that's my little brother out there. The tall one with the glasses.
We did it. We really did it. I can't believe it.
No!
Farewell, my paradise.
Hey, time to line up.
I can't, I can't walk.
Come on, Hilda.
Hey! What are you doing, please? Just look off me!
Thank you for the game!
What a game...
At least try to look sad.
Ushiwaka, you know, you're an enormous, emotionless bastard.
Thank you very much!
Would you say Karasano's number ten is about the same height as me?
Uh, uh, yeah, about.
Well, I suppose he'll keep growing, huh?
Although, the more ambitious his goals, the more he's going to struggle.
Sorry, Hinata. We tried to close out that straight, but didn't make it in time. Is your face okay?
Oh! I'm fine!
Don't give the scrub too much credit. The ball did come right to him, after all.
That Kageyama? He really played a tight game.
I didn't want to acknowledge that.
Although I think, that when Four Eyes came back, he laid out a game plan for everyone.
Yeah, something about closing out Ushiwaka's straights.
I'd assume that's why after his serve, Kageyama switched places with short stuff.
He was in the cross path.
And Nishinoya wasn't there to save the day.
So that's why he was prepared to set it so quickly, huh? Your pupil has learned your teachings well.
He's not my pupil!
And then on top of that, he somehow managed to adjust his tempo to synchronize with that erratic little shrimp.
He just pisses me off so much.
Well, if it makes you feel any better, I think they were only able to pull off this win thanks to that first year with the glasses.
I guess that little runt is definitely the kind of spiker you want to keep sending your sets.
Probably helps keep Kageyama on his toes.
Alright, well I say we get out of here.
I don't want to choke on my own barf at this awards ceremony.
You're still a piece of crap, you know that?
Yeah!
Thank you for coming to support us!
Thank you for coming!
Good job guys!
You guys are amazing!
You're going to be proof and proof!
Let's go!
He touched you!
Sugawara!
I'll see you again!
Congrats on the win!
Thank you everyone!
Hey man!
You okay?
Uh...
Yeah...
I can't wrap my head around it.
I never realized...
That we could lose.
Yeah...
I...
Don't think anyone else here did either.
Uh...
No...
I...
Uh...
After the ceremony, load the bus...
After the ceremony, load the bus.
We'll have our team huddle after we get back home.
Right.
Then, 100 serves for each of you.
Everyone, really great job.
I'm so, I'm so proud of you guys.
Dai Chi, amazing job.
Well done.
That three-man block was sweet.
Even if your thighs feel like they're splitting, handle the mid-air fights for me.
Just keeping my promise.
Tsukishima!
No matter what anyone else says, you, son, are the MVP today.
Well, it does get exhausting always being the MVP.
I'll let you carry the title today, Tsukishima.
You're more like the MVP in being loud and obnoxious.
Lushiwaka, I saw you got pissed off at the very end.
Normally, you would have either regrouped or let someone else go after it.
Gave me the chills watching your reaction.
I wanted to tell him personally that I'm stronger than he is.
Oh.
I wanted to rub it in.
Pretty immature of me.
Aren't most people's motivations pretty childish anyways?
That was a bad-ass trade.
I felt like I met a new Ushiwaka today.
I'm going to quit volleyball after high school.
But when I see you playing professionally on television, I'm going to brag to everyone that we were BFFs back in the day.
So make me proud, okay?
Sure.
And when they make a documentary about you, they can totally interview me as one of your old volleyball buddies.
Ushiwaka was so damn amazing.
Shouyo Hinata and Tobio Kageyama from the concrete.
We'll beat you next time.
Next time we go head-to-head, we'll still win!
And I'm going to make you admit that I'm even better than Oikawa!
Suki!
The ceremony's about to begin!
Is something wrong?
I said I was hoping to stop a few of his spikes, but I was only able to stop one.
I had five sets to do it, too.
I'm so...worthless.
Suki! You're not worthless!
What's wrong with you?
What?
Stop beating yourself up!
We're going to nationals!
But first, the ceremony!
Hm.
You're winners of the Miyagi Prefectural Playoffs, I present to you, Karasuno High School.
With their victory, this concludes the qualifying tournament for our area.
You will be the representatives for our prefecture at the High School Boys Spring National Tournament.
I present this award to commend you a great performance.
Congratulations.
Ladies and gentlemen, please give praise to both schools for their outstanding performance.
Let us also wish Karasuno High School the best of luck in January, when they will be attending the Spring National Playoffs in Tokyo.
So please join me in giving everyone a big, warm round of applause.
We're going!
To Spring Nationals!
Okay.
Okay, boys.
My uncles one-year-old toddler has better manners than these jokers.
Really scolding me.
Come on, you guys! You eating or you sleeping?
Oh, Coach! I'm so... I'm so happy!
Specs, that's awful sweet, but maybe you should slow down.
And that's probably the eighth time you've said that.
Hey, be careful not to break any dishes, okay?
From here on out, it's time to really buckle down.
We are going to get serious, Specs.
Hey, is it true that the volleyball club is headed to Nationals?
Wow, did you really not get to see the game?
You missed out. It was amazing.
Yeah?
Our volleyball team's, like, legendary once again.
Legendary?
I heard there's a really scary third-year student in the club.
I heard they also hang with a delinquent second-year, too.
I hope you're not a hostage, Hinata.
Their manager is, like, totally gorgeous, you guys.
No way.
So, where's the national tournament being held?
Tokyo's Metro Gym!
Whoa!
That's so cool!
I know, right?
Good grief. That idiot's already gotten a big head.
So that means you're going too, Hinata?
Of course!
Shouyo's in charge of everyone's stuff.
Like, gets lunches, carries the luggage.
So he's the scary dude's water boy?
Wrong! I play, thank you very much!
Oh, that's real cute.
Why is that so hard to believe?
Hey, what are you drawing there?
Hmm?
Starting on the volleyball club poster.
Oh?
Well, I'm going to head to our next class.
Okay, I'll be right there.
That looks kind of tough.
I didn't know that was part of the club manager's job.
Yeah.
But she makes it look kind of fun.
Tokyo's deciding their representative about now, aren't they?
Yeah.
They're playing now.
They whittle it down to four schools who then face off.
So we'll find out who's going sometime around mid-November.
I heard Fukuro Dani and Nekuma made the top four.
Making it all the way to the top four in Tokyo is really amazing, guys.
We were really lucky to have been able to play with some of them during training camp.
We are going to beat Nekuma, right, Kageyama?
It's only if they manage to make it through the qualifiers.
Uh, obviously they will.
It'll be the greatest match of all.
We'll face off at Spring Nationals.
We'll be right back.
Mr. Takata, you have a call in line, too.
Hi.
Uh, Takata speaking.
How are you?
All right.
Oh, yes.
Thank you for calling.
Yes.
That's right.
What are they doing?
They're measuring their vertical leap.
I think it's for statistics in the Spring Nationals brochure.
Oh.
I guess that's pretty interesting.
Kageyama, you're up.
Whoa.
Um.
132.6 inches.
So that puts Kageyama at number one, then.
Yep.
And just one more person to go.
Kageyama at number one, then.
I'm going to go.
How high'd I get?
Come on, tell us.
Wait a second, guys.
That's, um...
131.1.
All right.
That's as high as you got, Asahi.
I know.
Don't remind me.
I challenge you to a block-off, then.
Sure, loser buys Gung-Gun yogurt for a week.
You are on!
Is everyone here?
Gather up, boys.
Okay!
Everyone, nice work out there.
I came to tell you I have some big news.
Huh?
Kageyama.
You have been invited to participate in the National Youth Intensive.
Wow, that's big!
Whoa!
Oh!